Matt Vasquez

dwarfmondo.com 214. 502. 6766 mattvasquez@gmail.com 3737 Bunting Ave. Fort Worth, TX 76107

Profile

My name is Matt Vasquez. I'm a software developer living in Fort Worth, Texas. Most of my days are spent crafting software and leading development teams. I love what I do. There are two things that I am particularly passionate about; creating products that delight and promoting a team-centric culture for the companies I serve. I specialize in enterprise software design and development by solving problems with an elegant user experience and a development process that enables continuous delivery.

When I'm not typing on a keyboard you can find me on the golf course or outside with my wife and two kids enjoying some beautiful Texas weather.

Experience

FOUNDER, SCRUMMAGE, LLC (GETSCRUMMAGE.COM); FORT WORTH, TX - 2008-PRESENT

After trying many Scrum management tools to utilize at previous companies, I found that there wasn't a product on the market that met all of our needs as an agile development team. I began working on Scrummage in 2008 and continue to work on it today with an awesome team. We have served clients such as <u>The Verge</u>, <u>SB Nation</u> and <u>booking.com</u>.

My responsibilities include...

- Managing the Business
- Customer Support
- Hiring
- Software Development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman, SASS/SCSS, Backbone.js, MySQL)
- UI/UX Design

MANAGER OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, OGSYS; FORT WORTH, TX - 2013-PRESENT

I was brought onboard to provide technical leadership and mentoring to the development team creating the next generation product for the company. Responsibilities include user experience and visual design, implementing Scrum and agile practices, serving as Scrum Master, architect and writing code.

My responsibilities include...

- Scrum Master
- Hiring
- Architecture
- Software Development (C#, <u>ASP.NET</u> MVC, SASS/SCSS, Backbone.js, SQL Server)
- UI/UX Design

DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT, CAUSEMETRIC; ROGERS, AR - 2011-2013

Managed the development of a social giving platform called Pure Charity. Implemented the Scrum methodology and was Scrum Master, hired and managed development team members, wrote code (full stack developer).

My responsibilities include...

- Scrum Master
- Managing a remote team
- Hiring
- Architecture
- Software Development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SASS/SCSS, HAML, Backbone.js, PostgresSQL)
- UI/UX Design

UX MANAGER, THE ACTIVE NETWORK; IRVING, TX – 2010-2011

Through acquisition of Fellowship Technologies.

USER EXPERIENCE ARCHITECT, FELLOWSHIP TECHNOLOGIES; IRVING, TX - 2004-2010

I came onboard during the first 6 months of the company as a full stack .Net developer but moved into a user experience role a year or so later. I was also a member of the leadership team. Responsibilities included product design (visual and user experience), managing the UX team, working with engineering teams, font-end development including (HTML/CSS/JavaScript), full stack development.

My responsibilities include...

- UI/UX Design
- Managed UX Team
- Hiring
- Front-end Architecture
- Member of the leadership team
- Employee of The Year, 2007

CONSULTANT, HITACHI CONSULTING; DALLAS, TX – 2003-2004 DEVELOPER, HEALTHSOFT, INC; DALLAS, TX – 2002-2003

Education

University of North Texas, Denton, TX – Bachelor of Science, Business Computer Information Systems

Skills

Product Design (UI/UX), Full Stack Developer (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman, Sinatra, MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone, React, SASS/SCSS, CSS3, HTML5), Git.

Certified Scrum Master, 2013-Present, Scrum Alliance

References

Jeff Hook, COO, ParishSoft- (214) 668-9807, jeffhook@mac.com

Mike Rush, CEO, CauseMetric- (479) 381-0311, mike.rush@purecharity.com

Justin Patterson, Sr. Developer, Healthcare Payment Solutions- (817) 307-6341, justinpatterson@gmail.com